A Guide to the Records of the Choices and Challenges Forum, ca. 1985-2003
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Records of the Choices and Challenges Forum, ca. 1985-2003
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 15/27/1
16.81 Cubic Feet; 18 boxes and 4 reels
The Records of the Choices and Challenges Forum contain correspondence, meeting notes, articles, plays, advertisements, grant applications and reports, videos, audio tapes, and more from the development of the first 22 Choices and Challenges fora, from 1985 to 2003. The Choices and Challenges Forum at Virginia Tech was founded in 1985 by Doris Zallen, who served as its director until 2003. Each forum addresses the ethical and social issues created by advances in science, technology, and medicine.
Zallen, Doris T.
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Science and Technology Studies Department
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Records of the Choices and Challenges Forum was transferred to Special Collections in July 2018. Additional materials were transferred in May and June 2019.
Appraisal
Several items were removed from the collection and destroyed: duplicate items, empty photo envelopes and zip drive holder, blank and unused CDs and audiocassette tapes, software program CDs and instruction booklets, and an AV cord.
Historical Note
The Choices and Challenges Forum at Virginia Tech was founded in 1985 by Doris Zallen, who served as its director until 2003. Each forum addresses the ethical and social issues created by advances in science, technology, and medicine. The fora also examine the historical, philosophical, societal, and legal components.
Scope and Content
The Records of the Choices and Challenges Forum contain correspondence, meeting notes, articles, plays, advertisements, grant applications and reports, videos, audio recordings, and more from the development of the first 22 Choices and Challenges fora, from 1985 to 2003.
The records are divided into eight series, subdivided by forum: I. Doris Zallen, director files, ca. 1985-2003; II. Photographs, 1985-2003; III. Videos, 1985-2002; IV. Audiocassette Tapes, 1985-1989; and V. CDS, 1992-2001; VI. Floppy Disks, 1992-2003; VII. Posters, 1985-2003; VIII Teleconference Transcripts 1992-1997.
In the first series, Doris Zallen, director files, ca. 1985-2003, each forum files contains folders devoted to forum planning (with notes or items from the planning process), pre-forum publicity, correspondence related to planning and publicity, and items related to the awarding of continuing-education credits to doctors or other professionals. Additional material pertains to speakers and session leaders, such as CVs and correspondence, and to post-forum activities, including articles and evaluations. Some fora include materials related to teleconferencing, outreach, lessons plans, and other activities.
The second series, Photographs, 1985-2003, document forums 1-19 and 21-22.
The third series, Videos, 1985-2002, contains videocassettes and film reels from local tv programs, and the different panels at forums 1, 6, 8-19, and 21.
The fourth series, Audiocassette Tapes, 1985-1989, consists of audiocassettes of the different panels from forums 1, 2, 4, 5, 7, 12, and 15-18. This series also includes miscelaneous tapes in the "various tapes" file.
The fifth series, CDs, 1992-2001, contains Choices and Challenges website back ups and files from different fora.
The sixth series, Floppy Disks, 1992-2003, contain files from various fora.
The seventh series, Posters, 1985-2003, has forum posters as well as a poster about the project, "The Choices and Challenges Project - exploring the social and ethical dimensions of science and technology," from in between the 20th and 21st fora.
The last series, Teleconference Transcripts, 1992-1997, contian five transcripts for various forums.
Arrangement
The Records of the Choices and Challenges Forum are organized into the following series:
Series I. Doris Zallen, director files, ca. 1985-2003
Series II. Photographs, 1985-2003
Series III. Videoscassette Tapes, 1985-2002
Series IV. Audiocassette Tapes, 1985-1989
Series V. CDs, 1992-2001
Series VI. Floppy Disks, 1992-2003
Series VII. Posters, 1985-2003
Series VIII. Teleconference Transcripts, 1992-1997
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials
Doris Zallen Papers, Ms2018-032, Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Separated Materials
Copies of transcripts have been separated to the Rare Book Collection.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Science and Technology; University Archives; University History; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Science and Technology Studies Department
Contents List
- Series I. Doris Zallen, director files, ca. 1985-2003
  - Precursor to Choices and Challenges Forum [Science & Morality series, Nazareth College, Rochester, NY] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Selection of the Choices and Challenges Logo (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Final Report (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Scope and Contents
    Grant application and reports to the Virginia Foundation for the Humanities (VFH) for forums #1 thru #4
  - Forum 1: New Reproductive Options, 1985-02-28
    - Eval #1, Preprogram and Publicity (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Speaker Information and Correspondance (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Materials from C+C #1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Post Program Reports and Activities (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Forum 2: Weapons in Space, 1985-05-23
    - Publicity (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Choices and Challenges Weapons in Space, 1985-05 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Weapons in Space Speakers, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Post Forum and Follow Up (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Forum 3: Scientific and Technological Literacy, 1985-09-30
    - Speaker Info and Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Scientific and Technological Literacy, 1985-09-30 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Session Summaries and Handouts (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Post Forum and Follow-up (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Forum 4: Limits to Care - The Aged and Terminally Ill, 1985-11-20
    - Limits to Care - Pre-program Publicity (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Limits to Care - Special Information and Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Speakers (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Limits to Care - Summaries of Sessions and Handouts (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Limits to Care Transcript (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Limits to Care - Post Program Articles and Activities (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Choices and Challenges, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Grant application and reports for forums #5 thru #7 for the Virginia Foundation for the Humanities (VFH)
  - Forum 5: New Coal Mining and Combustion Technologies, 1986-04-04
    - Publicity and Planning (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Speaker Information (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Handouts and Transcripts (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Post-Forum (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Forum 6: Intelligence Testing, 1986-09-30
    - Publicity and Planning (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Speaker Information (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - IQ Testing, Handouts, and Summary (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Post-Forum Activities (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Forum 7: Genetic Engineering, 1986-11-20
    - Publicity (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Speaker and Presenter Information and Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Handouts (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Post-Forum Follow-Up, Activities, Assessment (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1987 Final Report, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Grant application and reports to Virginia Foundation for the Humanities (VFH)
  - Forum 8: Nuclear Power and Space Science, 1987-05-01
    - Pre-Forum Activities (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Nuclear Power - Space Science (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Nuclear Power and Space Science Post-Forum (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Forum 9: New Reproductive-Control Options, 1987-10-01
    - Anti-Reproductive Options (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Speakers and Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Handouts and Follow-Up (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Forum 10: Altering the Aging Process, 1988-04-14
    - GTE Grant (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Process, Planing, and Publicity (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Speaker Information and Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Handouts and Seminars (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Teleconference Materials and Evaluations (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Post-Program Follow-Up (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Forum 11: High-Temperature Superconductors, 1988-10-26
    - Pre-Program Publicity and Planning (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Speaker Information and Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Handouts and Follow-Up (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Teleconference and Evaluations (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Forum 12: The Pesticide Dilemma, 1989-11-29
    - Final Report 1989 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Pre-Program Planning and Publicity (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - PBS Materials,Teleconference (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Introduction, Speaker Notes, Handouts (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Speakers, Session Leaders, Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Discussion Groups at Virginia Tech (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Background Materials (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Forum 13: Food Fights: Dietary Alterations and Disease Prevention, 1990-04-19
    - Meeting Notes and Pre-Program Publicity (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - PBS Teleconference Information (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Forum Handouts, Session Summary, 1990-04 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Speaker Information and Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Post-Forum Materials, Follow-Up, Evaluations (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Forum 14: The Genie in the Genome: The Human Genome Project, 1992-04-09
    - National Institute of Health Application and Final Report (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Pre-Program Publicity, Planning, and Arrangements (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Teleconference Information (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Evaluation Information and Handouts (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Speakers, Conference (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Discussion Groups (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Background Materials (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1994-1997 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Forum 15: Quality of Life at the End of Life (Physician Assisted Suicide), 1994-03-24
    - Pre-Program Planning, Publicity and Meeting Notes (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Vignettes for Main Session (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Child Care Arrangements (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Teleconference 1/2 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Teleconference 2/2 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Forum Handouts (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Evaluations (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence and Speakers (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Forum 16: Quality of Life in the Electronic Village, 1995-03-30
    - Public Relations and Pre-Program Planning (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Forum Day Handouts, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Teleconference and PBS Contact (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Evaluations and Summary (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Speaker Biographies and Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Community Programming (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Background Materials (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Choices and Challenges 17 and 18
    - National Endowment for the Humanities Proposal, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities Interim Report, 1996-07 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Foundation for the Humanities Grant, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Forum 17: Quality of Life in the Global Environment: Water Resource, 1996-10-17
    - Early Publicity (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Handouts (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Teleconference (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Follow-Up (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Speaker Information and Forms (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Background (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Forum 18: Quality of Life in the Global Environment: Earth's Future, 1997-04-03
    - Publicity (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Speakers (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Teleconference (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Handouts and Post-Forum (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - PBS Contract (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Choices and Challenges 19
    - Virginia Foundation for the Humanities (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Forum 19: Reinventing the Human Designer Children, 1999-03-25
    - Planning (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Speakers, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Vignette (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Editing of Video - PBS (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Questions Raised by Audience at Main Session (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Reactions, Session Summaries (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Evaluations (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Forum 20: Reinventing the Human: The Six-Million-Dollar Body, 2000-11-09
    - Planning, Publicity, and Speaker Biographies (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Handouts (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Pig in the Middle Performance (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Post-Forum Production of PBS (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Forum 21: Food Fights: Genetically Modified Foods and Food Safety, 2002-04-11
    - Grant Application (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Greenwall Foundation (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Publicity (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Speakers (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Evaluation, Summaries (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Editing of Videotape for PBS (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Forum 22: Big Brother Technologies, 2003-03-27
    - Virginia Foundation for the Humanities Grant, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - NEH Proposal, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Pre-Program Planning, Publicity and Handouts (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Choices and Challenges Special Items
    - Plays (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Post-Forum, In the Classroom (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Forum Talks (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Post-Forum Learning Modules Online (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - In the Community (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - High Temperature Superconductors (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Forum Brochures (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - PBS Transcripts (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Quality of Life in the Global Environment: Preparing for the Next Century; Quality of Life At the End of Life; Quality of Life in the Electronic Village; The Genie in the Genome: the Human Genome Project; Quality of Life in the Global Environment: Sharing the Earth's Water Supply
  - Articles Regarding Choices and Challenges (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Awards (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Licensing Agreements (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Other Sources of Funds (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Local Media (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Problem with University Distinguished Professors' Forums (Box 6, Folder 17)
    The UDPs started a forum series and picked a subject (Climate Change) that the Choices and Challenges project had already selected and for which funding was awarded by the Virginia Foundation for the Humanities (VFH). This created the need to suddenly change the topic to "Pesticide Dilemma" and threatened funding from the VFH. The Presidential Symposia lasted only for a few years.
  - Advisory Committee Sampling and 1988 Survey of Consumer Topic Preferences, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - The Inner Life of Animals Brochure, 2009-11-05 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Series II. Photographs, 1985-2003
  - Forum 1: New Reproductive Options, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Forum 2: Weapons in Space, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Forum 3: Scientific and Technological Literacy, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Forum 4: Limits to Care, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Forum 5: Coal Technologies, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Forum 6: Intelligence Testing, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Forum 7: Genetic Engineering (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Forum 8: Nuclear Power and Space Science, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Forum 9: New Reproductive-Control Options, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Forum 10: Altering the Aging Process (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Forum 11: High Temperature Super Conductors, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Forum 12: Pesticide Dilemma, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Forum 13: Food Fights, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Forum 14: Human Genome Project (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Forum 15: Quality of Life at the End of Life (2 folders), 1994 (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
  - Forum 16: Quality of Life in the Electronic Village, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Forum 17: Quality of Life in the Global Environment: Water, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Forum 18: Quality of Life in the Global Environment: the Next Century (2 folders), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
  - Forum 19: Designer Children (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Forum 21: Food Frights, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Forum 22: Big Brother Technologies, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Various Photos
    - Choices and Challenges Forum Pictures and Brochures, 1988-1995 (Box 17, Folder 6-8)
    - Photographs from November 9, 2000, 2000-11-09 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Series III. Videos, 1985-2002
  - Local TV Programs Featuring Choices and Challenges Topics and Speakers (Box 8)
    One tape with 4 Standpoint Programs (Star Wars, Limits to Care, Coal, and IQ Testing) Standpoint Program on Nuclear Power and Space Science BlueRidge Nightline program on Limits-to-Care forum BlueRidge Nightline program on the Six-Million-Dollar-Man forum
  - Forum 1: New Reproductive Options, 1985 (Box 8)
    Gary Hodgen talk Noel Keane talk Q and AQ on use of surrogacy in pregnancy with Noel Keane and audience
    - Choices and Challenges Tape 1 - Wilfred Jewkes and Gary D. Hodgen, 1985 (Box 13)
    - Choices and Challenges Tape 2 - Discussion with Hodgen, Questions (Box 13)
    - Choices and Challenges Tape 3 - Discussion by Noel P. Keane, 1985
    - New Reproductive Options: Noel P. Keane, 1985-02-28 (Box 13)
  - Forum 6: Intelligence Testing, 1986 (Box 8)
    Arthur Jensen and Jonathan Baron talks with response by Richard Burian Arthur Jensen talk Jonathan Baron talk
    - Intelligence Testing Tape 1 (Box 12)
    - Intelligence Testing Tape 2 (Box 12)
    - Intelligence Testing Tape 3 (Box 12)
    - Intelligence Testing CEUT Edits Tape 1 (Box 12)
    - Intelligence Testing CEUT Edits Tape 2 (Box 12)
    - Intelligence Testing CEUT Edits Tape 3 (Box 12)
    - Intelligence Testing - Jonathan Baron Camera Original (Box 13)
    - Intelligence Testing Reactors, 1986-09-30
      Richard Burien, Lee Edson, William Harris, Frank Mac Hovec
    - Intelligence Testing #1 - D. Zallen, 1999-05-06 (Box 13)
  - Forum 8: Nuclear Power and Space Science, 1987 (Box 8)
    Richard Hirsh intro, Alvin Weinberg and Kristen Shrader-Frechette talks International Panel (UK, Sweden, and India) in Washington answering questions from Blacksburg audience
  - Forum 9: Reproductive-Control Options, 1987 (Box 8)
    Four vignettes, performed by Interplay, used to begin discussion by panelists
  - Forum 10: Altering the Aging Process, 1988 (Box 8)
    - Altering the Aging Process CEUT Edits Tape 1 (Box 12)
    - Altering the Aging Process CEUT Edits Tape 2 (Box 12)
    - Altering the Aging Process CEUT Edits Tape 3 (Box 12)
    - Aging Reel 2, 1988-04-14 (Box 12)
    - Aging Reel 1, 1988-04-14 (Box 12)
    - Aging Tape 1 of 3 (Box 12)
    - Aging Tape 2 of 3 (Box 12)
    - Aging Tape 3 of 3 (Box 12)
  - Forum 11: High Temperature Superconductors, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Forum 12: Pesticide Dilemma, 1989 (Box 8)
    Thomas Dunlap on history of pesticide use in the US General panel discussion on safety and effectiveness of pesticide use and on alternative strategies
  - Forum 13: Food Fights, 1990 (Box 8)
    - Food Fights CEUT Edits Tape 1 (Box 12)
    - Food Fights CEUT Edits Tape 2 (Box 12)
    - Food Fights CEUT Edits Tape 3 (Box 12)
    - Food Fights Teleconference Part 1 (Box 12)
    - Food Fights Teleconference Part 11 (Box 12)
    - Food Fights Tape 3 of 3 (Box 12)
    - Food Fights Tape 1 of 3 (Box 13)
    - Food Fights Tape 2 of 3, 1990 (Box 13)
  - Forum 14: Genie in the Genome, 1992 (Box 8)
    - The Genie in the Genome CEUT Edits Tape 1 (Box 12)
    - The Genie in the Genome CEUT Edits Tape 2 (Box 12)
    - The Genie in the Genome CEUT Edits Tape 3 (Box 12)
    - The Genie and the Genome Part 1 of 2, 1992-04-09 (Box 12)
    - The Genie and the Genome Part 2 of 2, 1992-04-09 (Box 12)
  - Forum 15: Quality of Life at the End of Life, 1994 (Box 8)
    Vignette 1 and panel discussion on physician-assisted suicide Vignette 2 and panel discussion on proceeding with futile interventions Vignettes, 1 and 2 only
    - Quality of Life at the End of Life Tape 1 of 2, 1995-03-24 (Box 12)
    - Quality of Life at the End of Life Tape 2 of 2, 1995-03-24 (Box 12)
    - End of Life Tape 3 of 3 (Box 12)
    - Blue Ridge Nighttime: Quality of Life at the End of Life (Box 12)
    - PBS Adult Learning Satellite Service & Virginia Tech - Quality of Life at the End of Life, 1994-03-24 (Box 13)
  - Forum 16: Quality of Life in the Electronic Village, 1995 (Box 8)
    Panel discussion on education, the workplace, and medicine Panel discussion on issues of equity Donald Lindberg discusses telemedicine, including "Nintendo surgery"
    - Quality of Life in the Electronic Village Tape 1 of 2, 1995-03-30 (Box 12)
    - Quality of Life in the Electronic Village Tape 2 of 2, 1995-03-30 (Box 12)
    - Electronic Village Tape 1 of 4 (Box 12)
    - Electronic Village Tape 2 of 4 (Box 12)
    - Electronic Village Tape 3 of 4 (Box 12)
    - Electronic Village Tape 4 of 4 (Box 12)
    - Quality of Life in the Electronic Village CEUT Edits Tape 2 (Box 12)
    - Blue Ridge Nighttime: Quality of Life in the Electronic Village, 1995-03-24 (Box 12)
    - Blacksburg Electronic Village (Box 12)
  - Forum 17: Sharing the Earth's Water Supply, 1996 (Box 8)
  - Forum 18: Preparing for the Next Century, 1997 (Box 8)
    - Quality of Life in the Global Environment: Preparing For the Next Century Part 1 of 2, 1997-04-03 (Box 12)
    - Quality of Life in the Global Environment: Preparing For the Next Century Part 2 of 2, 1997-04-03 (Box 12)
  - Forum 19: Designer Children (Box 8)
    Animation explaining gene therapy and genetic enhancement Edited program based on the main conference session
  - Forum 21: Food Frights, 2002 (Box 8)
    Edited program based on the main conference session
    - Food Frights Program with TC Captions (Box 12)
      24:30:15
  - Various Tapes
    - Choices and Challenges: Human Organ Transplants "Alternatives to Human Organs" (Box 12)
    - Choices and Challenges Panel Discussion - The Extended Ecosystem (Box 12)
    - Choices and Challenges Panel Discussion - The Workplace Environment (Box 12)
    - Choices and Challenges Excerpts Postel (Box 12)
    - Choices and Challenges Excerpts Hammond (Box 12)
    - Rep. Boucher, 1995-03-22 (Box 13)
    - Quality of Life Interviews (Box 12)
    - Spliced Tape for Choices and Challenges, 1994 (Box 12)
    - Author Jewsey Camera Original (Box 13)
    - Choices and Challenges Weapons in Space - Questions Period - Camera Original, 1985-05-23 (Box 13)
      James A Ionson, John E Pike, Robert E Marshak (moderator)
    - Production and Inventory Theory, 1986-03 (Box 13)
    - "What About Tomorrow?" (Box 13)
    - Unnamed Tape (Box 13)
    - Choices and Challenges Q&A, 2000-11-09 (Box 18)
    - Choices and Challenges Main Session, 2000-11-09 (Box 18)
    - Choices and Challenges: Reinventing the Human the Six Million Dollar Body Program 1 of 2, 2000 (Box 18)
    - Choices and Challenges: Reinventing the Human the Six Million Dollar Body TC Window Dub Program 1 of 2, 2000 (Box 18)
    - Unnamed Tape (Box 18)
    - Unnamed Tape (Box 18)
  - Film Reels
    - Choices and Challenges: Quality of Life at the End of Life Part 1 (Item 2)
    - Choices and Challenges: Quality of Life at the End of Life Part 2 (Item 3)
    - Choices and Challenges Teleconference Reel 1 of 2, 1988-10-26 (Item 1)
    - Choices and Challenges Teleconference Reel 2 of 2, 1988-10-26 (Item 4)
- Series IV. Audiocassette Tapes, 1985-1989
  - Forum 1: New Reproductive Options, 1985 (Box 9)
    Gary Hodgen talk on new reproductive options; Q and A with Gary Hodgen; Noel Keane talk on use of surrogate parenthood
  - Forum 2: Weapons in Space, 1985 (Box 9)
    Talks by James Ionson and John Pike; Discussion with Ionson and Pike; Ionson and Pike discussion (continued)
  - Forum 4: Limits to Care, 1985 (Box 9)
    Panel discussion of a case study; Panel discussion (continued)
  - Forum 5: New Coal Mining and Combustion Technologies, 1986 (Box 9)